wooga.com 2019-10-29

# Privacy Policy - Wooga

**Privacy Policy for our Games**

Wooga GmbH, Saarbruecker Strasse 38, 10405 Berlin, Germany (“Wooga” or “we”), is a developer and publisher of games and mobile game applications that are made available via app stores including the Apple App Store, Google Play Store and Amazon Appstore, and other platforms such as Facebook (our “Games”). Wooga is responsible for providing Games and related services (such as support services, our website, competitions, newsletters, advertising etc.) (collectively, the “Services”) and for data processing. Wooga was recently acquired by the Israeli game developer and publisher, Playtika, and is now a subsidiary of the parent company. On the basis of data protection agreements, certain data is transferred within the companies that is necessary for the business performance of both companies. If you would like to find out more about Wooga and our Services, please visit the Imprint section of the Games or our Website  [www.wooga.com](https://www.wooga.com/) or [www.playtika.com](http://www.playtika.com/) .

In this data privacy policy, we will share what “personal data” or “personally identifiable data” mean, how we collect and what we do with the data, and why we do so. We will also let you know how we protect your data, when data will be deleted and which rights you as a data subject have. Personal data in this context are all individual information about personal or objective circumstances of a specific or identifiable natural person, e.g. your name, address or e-mail address, but also IP addresses and device-related identifiers. When you use our Games or access our Services, personal data is processed. 

We hope to unite people in fun and enjoyment through our Games, so we create games that you can play and share with other people. This means that our Services can be accessed and shared with friends or in social networks. We believe that data protection is as important as uniting people through our Games and, therefore, we aim to protect your privacy as best as we can. If you use third party services - for example while playing one of our Games on Facebook - please note that those service providers will also collect personal data, that is not part of our service. 

 **Who can I contact?**

Wooga GmbH is responsible for their Services and for the protection of your data as a player. You can reach us at:

Wooga GmbH  
Saarbruecker Straße 38  
10405 Berlin, Germany

Phone: +49-30-52107050  
Fax: +49-30-89649064  
Mail: [info@wooga.com](mailto:info@wooga.com)

If you have specific questions about your personal data, deletion of your personal data or similar things, you can contact our Data Privacy Officer via e-mail at [privacy@wooga.net](mailto:privacy@wooga.net).

 **What are my rights?**

You can contact us at any time if you have any questions about your rights regarding data protection or if you wish to exercise any of the following rights:

 **Right to withdraw your consent  **in accordance with Art. 7 para. 3 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you wish to cancel a previously given consent to a newsletter)

 **Right to access your data  **in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you would like to know what data we have stored about you)

 **Right to correct your data  **in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if your e-mail address has changed and we should replace your old e-mail address)

 **Right to have your data deleted  **in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you want us to delete certain data that we have stored about you)

 **Right to limit data collection  **in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you do not want us to use your e-mail address for newsletters, but only to send absolutely necessary e-mails)

 **Right to take your data with you  **in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us to receive your data, if you want to upload it to another service)

 **Right to object how your data is handled  **in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you do not agree with any user analytics procedures as described within this privacy policy)

 **Right to send complaints  **to the supervisory authority in accordance with Art. 77 para. 1 GDPR (e.g. you can contact the data protection supervisory authority directly)

 **Deletion of data and storage periods**

Unless otherwise stated, we will delete or anonymise your data as soon as it is no longer needed (e.g. your e-mail address after you have unsubscribed from our newsletter). Your data will also be deleted or anonymised automatically, if and when the mandatory storage period expires (e.g. those required by law for payment transactions). Such data may be needed for longer periods of time for legal reasons. You can request information about all personal data we have stored about you.

 **Data collected in our Games**

When you use our Services, we collect and store certain data about you to provide our Games and Services, to improve your overall user experience and to provide you with customised offers (e.g. certain in-game offers that you might like based on your playing behaviour):

Temporary unique device identifiers (e.g. IDFA and Android ID) and random device identification numbers (client IDs) and user identification numbers (user IDs)

Progress in the game and playing behaviour (e.g. how fast you reached a certain level or how you decorated your island)

In-app purchases (e.g. how many Diamonds you purchased for which price)

Game version (e.g. v1.23.111)

Language Settings (e.g. system language English)

IP address (e.g. 96.92.316.example or 2a02:7122:8337:1112:bdb2:651f:example)

Approximate location based on IP range (e.g. “Berlin & surrounding area”)

Internet provider (e.g. “Unity Media“ or “Deutsche Telekom“)

Internet connection speed (e.g. 120 Mbit)

Date and time of your game session (e.g. 11:45 on 25.05.2018)

Browser and version (e.g. Chrome v65 or Safari 11.1)

Operating system (e.g. MacOS, Android)

Hardware (e.g. Intel processor)

You may be aware that your IP address and other unique identifiers can theoretically be traced back to you or to the device you are playing on. _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , we delete or anonymise identifiers in our database and most of the technical data after your game session. Any other data will only be used for statistical purposes to optimise the game, to serve interest-based ads (more information can be found below under “(Personalised) Advertising”) and to offer a more personalised gaming experience to you as our players (e.g. automatically setting the difficulty depending on your playing behaviour). _The purpose  _of temporarily storing this data is to establish a connection with our game servers which is necessary for providing our Games and Services as well as to provide a more personalised gaming experience to you. _The legal basis  _are the contract with you in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR and also the legitimate interest in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. In addition, we apply the aforementioned safeguards to protect your data. 

**Mobile app and app permissions**

When downloading our Games as mobile apps or purchasing in-app items inside the Games through an app platform (e.g. Apple App Store or Google Play Store), you submit certain information to that platform, in particular your account data, e.g. your name, device identifiers, e-mail address and payment information. We have no influence on this data collection and are not responsible for it.

Some features of our Games require the app to access certain functions and services on your device. Depending on which mobile operating system you are using, this may require you to accept certain app permissions. We will now explain to you what those permissions are as follows:

 **iOS**

Push notifications: If you select OK in the “Allow push notifications” pop up, you allow the app to notify you of certain events inside the game, even if the app is not currently open. You will then receive alerts as sounds, messages and/or symbol indicators (an image or a number on the app icon).

Game Center: We also provide a connection to the Game Center service from Apple, which is subject to Apple's Privacy Policy, available at [https://www.apple.com/privacy](https://www.apple.com/privacy/). When you use the service, e.g. to receive notifications about achievements, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You need to consider which personal information you choose to submit.

 **Android**

External Storage (Change or delete the contents of your external storage, read the contents of your external storage): These functions allow the app to temporarily store content on your device. The app only uses its own memory storage for this purpose. Other data on the external storage will not be erased, modified or read.

Internet Connection (Get Internet data, view full network access, network and Wi-Fi connections): These functions allow the app to obtain data from the Internet and to determine whether a connection to the Internet exists via a Wi-Fi network or via a mobile data connection. This is to prevent that larger amounts of data may use too much of limited data volumes.

Deactivate hibernation: This function allows the app to deactivate the idle state of the phone (e.g. to display videos without switching off the screen).

 _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , all app permissions are optional, except for the technical permissions needed for the app to run. You can always decline (by clicking “no” or “do not accept” in your device settings). You can also revoke app permissions afterwards by changing the corresponding settings on your device. _The purpose  _of asking for those app permissions is to keep you and the game updated on game updates, game related news and notifications. _The legal basis  _is your consent in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

 **Connecting with Facebook**

You can play some of our Games directly on Facebook or connect the game with your Facebook account details. If you do either of those, you will be able to use your Facebook account to log in on multiple devices and synchronise your saved game status across different devices. We will not store your friends lists and contacts and there is no permanent link between the game and your Facebook account, you can always disconnect your Facebook profile from the game you are playing. The underlying service is provided by Facebook and further details can be found in Facebook’s Privacy Policy (<http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>). The connection with Facebook will not allow us to post anything to your Facebook page without your permission. We will receive some of the following Facebook account information, depending on what you choose to provide:

Public profile information (e.g. Facebook name, your profile picture and other public information etc.)

Friends list (friends you are connected with on Facebook)

E-Mail address (the e-mail address you use to log in to Facebook)

Facebook game specific ID related to your profile and the game you are playing (not your Facebook ID)

We use this information to improve your gaming experience (e.g. you can see which of your friends are playing the same game as you are and the other way around) and also for market research and advertising, but only following anonymisation.

 _As a safeguard to protect your privacy and the privacy of your friends_ , Facebook lets you choose which of your Facebook information you want to share with us (except for the required profile information) and we ensure that personal information is deleted or anonymised, so that it cannot be traced back to you in our systems. Since some of the Facebook services are located in the USA and thus in a country outside the EU and the EEA (a third country), further safeguards are required to ensure that your data is protected in accordance with a European level of data protection. Facebook has been certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield for the ad-related services and has thus demonstrated a sufficient level of data protection (<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacyshield>).  _The purpose  _of collecting and storing this information is to connect you with your friends on Facebook, to provide you with a cross-platform gaming experience, to synchronise your saved game status and to offer personalised advertising. _The legal basis_  is your consent – when choosing to connect your Facebook account - in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

 **Support and contact form**

We work with Helpshift Inc. (“Helpshift”), based in the United States, which provides an online helpdesk and in-app support system. When you contact us for support, the below information will be handled by Helpshift strictly in accordance with our instructions: 

Game you are playing

Your name or nickname

Your e-mail address 

Platform you are playing on

Your type of issue

Your language

Your user ID or Facebook game specific ID

Your problem description

Your uploaded file (optional)

Helpshift also automatically collects additional types of information, such as your IP address and data sent by your device to provide and improve their service (further information can be found in this Privacy Policy under “Data collected in our Games” or within the Helpshift Privacy Policy: https://www.helpshift.com/legal/privacy). The information is then transferred to a Helpshift server in the United States. _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , we arranged a data processing agreement with Helpshift in accordance with Art. 28 GDPR, where we ensure that your personal information is only used in accordance with our instructions and not for their own purposes. In addition, your request is submitted via an encrypted connection and we apply the principle of data minimisation to collect only such data that is actually required to best answer your support request. The content of your request will be stored as long as you are an active player of our Games, so you can get a faster response in case you have a similar problem in the future. _The purpose_  of using the service from Helpshift is to answer the extensive number of user requests we receive. Helpshift helps us to improve our customer service so that you can get a faster and helpful response. _The legal basis_  are the contract with you in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR and the legitimate interest in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR, which we evaluated together with our data protection officer. We also provide aforementioned safeguards to protect your data.

 **(Personalised) Advertising**

We use advertising technologies in our Games and exchange ad identifiers with external advertising networks to allow personalised advertising within our Games. We and our trusted partners collect and process the Apple Advertising ID (IDFA) on iOS devices and the Google Advertising ID on Android devices to allow interest-based advertising and measure the success of aforementioned advertising. Advertising IDs are unique but at the same time non-personalised and non-permanent identification numbers provided by your operating system and device. We will now explain how to activate or deactivate the advertising technologies within the mobile apps as follows:

 **iOS**

Open the "Settings" application of iOS and select the "Privacy" menu item and then the "Advertising" sub-item. If you activate the "Limit ad tracking" option, we can only take limited measures such as identifying unique users or combating fraud. In the same menu you can always delete the IDFA ("Reset Ad-ID"), then a new ID is created which is not merged with the data collected earlier. 

**Android**

Open the “Settings” application and select the “Google” menu item. Depending on your device, this option may not be visible on the main menu but you may use the search function at the top of the Settings menu to find it. From there, select the “Ads” sub-item and activate the option “Opt out of Ads Personalisation” to prevent the creation of profiles and the display of interest-based advertising. You can delete the advertising ID in the same menu at any time (“Reset advertising ID”), then a new ID will be created which will not be merged with the previously collected data.

 _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , we only store personal information temporarily. Additionally, the user can deactivate interest-based advertising in the device settings as described above. We also ensure that our external service providers are committed to a high level of data protection by concluding data protection agreements. _The purpose_  is to improve our Games and provide the player with more relevant ads. The information collected helps us to improve our websites and Games and – at the same time – keep our Games free for a wide player base. _The legal basis_  is the legitimate interest in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR, which we evaluated together with our data protection officer. In addition, a data processing agreements were concluded with external ad technology providers networks in accordance with the requirements of Art. 28 GDPR.

 **Last updated: May 2018**

 **Our Website’s Privacy Policy**

Welcome to Wooga.com! 

Wooga GmbH, Saarbruecker Strasse 38, 10405 Berlin, Germany (“Wooga” or “we”), is a developer and publisher of games and mobile game applications that are made available via app stores including the Apple App Store, Google Play Store and Amazon Appstore, and other platforms such as Facebook (our “Games”). Wooga is responsible for providing Games and related services (such as this website, support services, competitions, newsletters, advertising etc.) (collectively, the “Services”) and for data processing. If you would like to find out more about Wooga and our Services, please visit the Imprint section of the Games or on this Website  _www.wooga.com/imprint/_

In this data privacy policy, we will share what “personal data” or “personally identifiable data” mean, how we collect data when you visit our websites (e.g.  _[www.wooga.com](https://www.wooga.com/)_ ) and what we do with the data, and why we do so. We will also let you know how we protect your data, when data will be deleted and which rights you as a data subject have. Personal data in this context are all individual information about personal or objective circumstances of a specific or identifiable natural person, e.g. your name, address or e-mail address, but also IP addresses and device-related identifiers. When you use our Games or access our Services, personal data is processed. You can find out more about that in our Games Privacy Policy.

 **Who can I contact?**

Wooga GmbH is responsible for this website and their Services, as well as for the protection of your data. You can reach us at:

Wooga GmbH  
Saarbruecker Straße 38  
10405 Berlin, Germany

Phone: +49-30-52107050  
Fax: +49-30-89649064  
Mail: [info@wooga.com](mailto:info@wooga.com)

If you have specific questions about your personal data, deletion of your personal data or similar things, you can contact our Data Privacy Officer via e-mail [p](mailto:privacy@wooga.net)[rivacy@wooga.net](mailto:privacy@wooga.net).

 **What are my rights?**

You can contact us at any time if you have any questions about your rights regarding data protection or if you wish to exercise any of the following rights:

 **Right to withdraw your consent  **in accordance with Art. 7 para. 3 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you wish to cancel a previously given consent to a newsletter)

 **Right to access your data  **in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you would like to know what data we have stored about you)

 **Right to correct your data  **in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if your e-mail address has changed and we should replace your old e-mail address)

 **Right to have your data deleted  **in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you want us to delete certain data that we have stored about you)

 **Right to limit data collection  **in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you do not want us to use your e-mail address for newsletters, but only to send absolutely necessary e-mails)

 **Right to take your data with you  **in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us to receive your data, if you want to upload it to another website)

 **Right to object how your data is handled  **in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR (e.g. you can contact us if you do not agree with any user analytics procedures as described within this privacy policy)

 **Right to send complaints  **to the supervisory authority in accordance with Art. 77 para. 1 GDPR (e.g. you can contact the data protection supervisory authority directly)

 **Deletion of data and storage periods**

Unless otherwise stated, we will delete or anonymise your data as soon as it is no longer required (e.g. your e-mail address after you have unsubscribed from our newsletter). Your data will also be deleted or anonymised automatically if a certain storage period expires (e.g. those required by law for payment transactions). Such data may be needed for longer periods of time for legal reasons. You can request information about all personal data we have stored about you.

 **Visiting our website**

When you visit our website  _[www.wooga.com](https://www.wooga.com/)_ , we collect the data that your browser sends to us:

IP address (e.g. 96.92.316.example or 2a02:7122:8337:1112:bdb2:651f:example)

Approximate location based on IP range (e.g. “Berlin & surrounding area”)

Internet provider (e.g. „Unity Media“ or „Deutsche Telekom“)

Internet connection speed (e.g. 120 Mbit)

Date, time and duration of visit (e.g. 11:45 on 25.05.2018)

Last visited website (e.g. google.com)

Browser and version (e.g. Chrome v65 or Safari 11.1)

Operating system (e.g. Mac OS)

Hardware (e.g. Intel processor)

You may be aware that your IP address can theoretically be traced back to you.  _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , we delete or anonymise your IP address after your visit. Therefore, all other data possibly attached to it can no longer be traced back to you. It will only serve anonymous and statistical purposes to optimise our website.  _The purpose_  of temporarily storing this data is necessary to establish a connection as well as loading our website the way it was designed to. Such data is therefore required to display the website on your screen, to avoid display problems and other technical error messages.  _The legal basis_ is the legitimate interest in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. In addition, we apply the aforementioned safeguards to protect your data.

 **Contact forms**

When you contact us directly via e-mail we store your e-mail address and content of your message in order to answer your request. These will be deleted as soon as they are no longer needed for and delete it afterwards.

We work with Helpshift, an external online helpdesk and in-app support system provided by Helpshift Inc. (“Helpshift”), a company based in San Francisco, California. When you contact us via the contact forms in the Support section on our website, the below information will be handled by Helpshift strictly in accordance with our instructions:

Game you are playing

Your name or nickname

Your e-mail address

Platform you are playing on

Your type of issue

Your language

Your user ID or Facebook game specific ID

Your problem description

Your uploaded file (optional)

Helpshift also automatically collects additional types of information, such as your IP address and data sent by your device to provide and improve their service (further information can be found in this Privacy Policy under “Data collected in our Games” or within the Helpshift Privacy Policy: <https://www.helpshift.com/legal/privacy>). The information is then transferred to a Helpshift server in the United States.  _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , we arranged a data processing agreement with Helpshift in accordance with Art. 28 GDPR, where we ensure that your personal information is only used in accordance with our instructions and not for their own purposes. In addition, your request is submitted via an encrypted connection and we apply the principle of data minimisation to collect only such data that is actually required to best answer your support request. The content of your request will be stored as long as you are an active player of our Games, so you can get a faster response in case you have a similar problem in the future.  _The purpose_  of using the service from Helpshift is to answer the extensive number of user requests we receive. Helpshift helps us to improve our customer service so that you can get a faster and helpful response.  _The legal basis_  are the contract with you in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR and the legitimate interest in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR, which we evaluated together with our data protection officer. We also provide aforementioned safeguards to protect your data.

 **Job application**

You have the option of applying for an open position at Wooga through external websites and our job pages. To apply for a job at Wooga, we need the following information from you:

Your first name

Your last name

Your e-mail address

Your phone number ( _optional_ )

Your uploaded resume or cv

Your cover letter ( _optional_ )

Your LinkedIn profile or website ( _optional_ )

Your portfolio ( _optional_ )

Your skype details ( _optional_ )

Information related to how you heard about us ( _you can select “other” if you do not want to tell us_ )

Additionally, you can click  **Apply with LinkedIn** , where the job application fields will be automatically filled with corresponding data from your LinkedIn profile and make your complete profile available to us. We will then be able to easily access and see your LinkedIn profile information. Further information can be found here <https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/72063> and in the LinkedIn privacy policy that can be found here <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

We use a recruiting tool provided by Greenhouse Software, Inc., based in New York, USA.  _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , the information and files you provide are submitted through an encrypted connection and will only be used for internal recruiting purposes. We also apply the principle of data minimisation and only ask for information that is actually required for our recruiting process. The information you provide will only be stored for as long as we need it for the recruiting process and be deleted six months after we have received your application at the latest. We arranged a data processing agreement with Greenhouse in accordance with Art. 28 GDPR, where we ensure that your personal information is only used in accordance with our instructions and not for their own purposes. Greenhouse has been certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield and has thus demonstrated a sufficient level of data protection ( _<https://www.greenhouse.io/privacy-shield-notice>_ ). The p _urpose_  of collecting and storing aforementioned data is only for recruiting. The reason for extended storage is based on German legal requirements.  _The legal basis_  is Section 26 BDSG-new (German Data Protection Act), which allows the processing of employee and applicant data when it is necessary to make a hiring decision. The basis for connecting and accessing the LinkedIn profile is your consent as given when clicking “Apply with LinkedIn”.

 **Newsletter**

You have the opportunity to submit your e-mail address, so that we can send you gaming related news and newsletters.

 _As a safeguard to protect your privacy and the privacy of others_ , we use the double-opt-in mechanism before we send out our newsletter. You will receive a link from us to confirm your subscription and e-mail address. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the e-mail or by contacting us using the above contact details.  _The purpose  _of collecting and storing your e-mail address is solely for sending you our gaming related news and the newsletter.  _The legal basis  _is your consent - provided to us through the double-opt-in mechanism - in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

 **Cookies**

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files that are usually stored in a folder from your browser. Cookies contain information about the current or last visit to our website:

Name of the website

Expiration date of the cookie

Random value

If cookies do not contain an exact expiration date, they are stored only temporarily and are automatically deleted as soon as you close your browser or restart your device. Cookies with an expiration date will still be stored even when you close your browser or restart your device. Such cookies will not be deleted until the specified date or if you delete them manually.

We use the following three types of cookies on our website:

required cookies (cookies that are required, e.g. to display the website correctly for you and to store certain settings temporarily)

functional and performance-related cookies (cookies that help us improve our website, e.g. to evaluate technical data of your visit and avoid error messages)

advertising and analytics cookies (cookies that provide analytics and personalized ads, e.g. advertising for shoes is displayed if you have previously searched for shoes)

You can configure, block and delete cookies in your browser settings. If you delete all cookies from our website, some functions of the website may not be displayed correctly. Further information on cookies and how to configure them can be found here in [German https://www.bsi-fuer-buerger.de](https://www.bsi-fuer-buerger.de/BSIFB/DE/Empfehlungen/EinrichtungSoftware/EinrichtungBrowser/Sicherheitsmassnahmen/Cookies/cookies_node.html%20) or here in English <https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/>.

 **Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google Analytics uses the advertising and analytics cookies described above to analyse our website with regard to your usage behaviour. The information generated by these cookies is transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, your IP address is shortened before the usage statistics are evaluated, so that no direct connection to you as a person can be made. For this purpose, we use the "anonymizeIp" function to ensure anonymous collection of IP addresses. Google will use the anonymous information collected by the cookies to evaluate the usage of the website and to compile reports on website activity. Google may also transfer this information to third parties if this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google.

You can also configure your browser to refuse cookies, or you can prevent Google from collecting and analysing the data by downloading and installing a browser plug-in (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>) from Google. As an alternative to the browser add-on or within browsers on mobile devices, you can set an opt-out cookie to prevent future collection by Google Analytics within this website (the opt-out only works in the browser and only for this domain). If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this link again.

 _As a safeguard to protect your privacy_ , we use the anonymisation feature offered by Google as mentioned above, whereas analytics are not based on you as a person, but only on a statistical basis. In addition, the high security standards of the Google platform and its data privacy policy apply (<http://www.google.com/intl/de-DE/privacy>). We have also concluded a special data protection agreement with Google, which ensures to protect your data through technical and organizational security measures. Since Google is based in the USA and thus in a third country, further safeguards are required to ensure that your data is protected in accordance with a European level of data protection. Google has been certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield and has thus demonstrated a sufficient level of data protection (<https://www.google.de/policies/privacy/frameworks/>).  _The purpose_  of the use of Google Analytics is to (anonymously) analyse usage behaviour of our websites. The information collected helps us to improve our websites and games. _The legal basis  _is the legitimate interest in accordance with the European data protection requirements under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR, which we evaluated together with our data protection officer. In addition, a data processing agreement was concluded in accordance with the requirements of Art. 28 GDPR.

Last updated: March 2019

 **Datenschutzerklärung für unsere Spiele**

Die Wooga GmbH, Saarbrücker Straße 38, 10405 Berlin, Deutschland („Wooga“ oder „wir“), ist Entwickler und Publisher von Spielen und mobilen Spiele-Apps, die über App-Stores wie den iTunes App Store, Google Play und Amazon Appstore und andere Plattformen wie Facebook (unsere „Spiele“) verfügbar gemacht werden. Wooga ist verantwortlich für die Bereitstellung von der Spiele und verwandten Angeboten (wie z.B. Support, unsere Webseite, Gewinnspiele, Newsletter, Werbung usw.) (zusammen die „Services“) und ist verantwortlich für die Verarbeitung der Daten. Wooga wurde kürzlich vom israelischen Spieleentwickler und -herausgeber Playtika übernommen und ist nun eine Tochtergesellschaft des Mutterkonzerns. Auf der Grundlage von Datenschutzbestimmungen werden innerhalb der Unternehmen bestimmte Daten übertragen, die für den Geschäftserfolg beider Unternehmen erforderlich sind. Wenn du mehr über Wooga oder Playtika und unsere Services erfahren möchtest, kannst du das Impressum unserer Spiele oder unsere Webseite  [ www.wooga.com](https://www.wooga.com/) oder [ www.playtika.com](http://www.playtika.com/) besuchen.

In dieser Datenschutzerklärung teilen wir Dir mit, was „personenbezogene Daten“ oder „personenbeziehbare Daten“ bedeutet, wie wir Daten erfassen und was wir mit ihnen machen und warum. Wir informieren auch darüber, wie wir deine Daten schützen, wann Daten gelöscht werden und welche Rechte als betroffene Person du hast. Personenbezogene Daten sind in diesem Zusammenhang alle Einzelangaben über persönliche oder sachliche Verhältnisse einer bestimmten oder bestimmbaren natürlichen Person, z.B. Name, Anschrift oder E-Mail-Adresse, aber auch IP-Adressen und gerätebezogene Kennungen. Wenn Du unsere Spiele nutzt oder auf unsere Services zugreifst, werden personenbezogene Daten verarbeitet.

Wir wollen mit unseren Spielen Menschen in Spaß und Freude vereinen, daher entwickeln wir Spiele, die du mit anderen Menschen spielen und teilen kannst. Das bedeutet, dass unsere Services mit Freunden geteilt oder in sozialen Netzwerken genutzt werden können. Wir glauben, dass Datenschutz genauso so wichtig ist wie Menschen durch unsere Spiele zusammenzubringen, und deshalb sind wir bestrebt, deine Privatsphäre so gut wie möglich zu schützen. Wenn du Dienste Dritter nutzt - zum Beispiel beim Spielen eines unserer Spiele auf Facebook – beachte bitte, dass diese Dienste zusätzlich personenbezogene Daten erheben, die nicht zu unserem Angebot gehören.

 **An wen kann ich mich wenden?**

Wooga GmbH ist verantwortlich ihre Services und für den Schutzer deiner Daten als Spieler. Du erreichst uns unter: 

 **Wooga GmbH** **  
Saarbrücker Straße 38  
10405 Berlin, Germany**

 **  
** **Phone: +49-30-52107050** **  
Fax: +49-30-89649064  
Mail: [info@wooga.com](mailto:info@wooga.com)**

Falls du konkrete Fragen zu deinen Daten, deren Löschung oder Ähnlichem hast, kannst du zu unseren Datenschutzbeauftragten über [privacy@wooga.net](mailto:privacy@wooga.net) Kontakt aufnehmen. 

 **Was sind meine Rechte?**

Du kannst dich jederzeit an uns wenden mit Fragen zu deinen Rechten in Bezug auf den Schutzer deiner Daten oder wenn du eines deiner nachfolgenden Rechte geltend machen möchtest:

 **Widerrufsrecht** Art. 7 Abs. 3 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, falls du eine zuvor erteilte Einwilligung zum Erhalt eines Newsletters rückgängig machen möchtest)

 **Recht auf Auskunft** Art. 15 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, falls du wissen möchtest, welche personenbezogenen Daten wir über dich gespeichert haben)

 **Berichtigung** Art. 16 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, falls deine E-Mail-Adresse sich geändert hat und wir die alte E-Mail-Adresse ersetzen sollen)

 **Löschung** Art. 17 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, falls wir bestimmte Daten löschen sollen, die wir über dich gespeichert haben)

 **Einschränkung der Verarbeitung** Art. 18 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, falls du nicht möchtest, dass wir deine E-Mail-Adresse für den Newsletterversand verwenden, stattdessen nur noch zur Versendung unbedingt erforderlicher E-Mails)

 **Datenübertragbarkeit** Art. 20 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, um du deine bei uns gespeicherten Daten erhalten möchtest, wenn du die Daten in einen anderen Service uploaden willst)

 **Widerspruch** Art. 21 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich an uns wenden, falls du mit einem der hier angegebenen Nutzeranalyseverfahren nicht einverstanden bist)

 **Beschwerderecht** bei der zuständigen Aufsichtsbehörde gem. Art. 77 Abs. 1 DSGVO (z.B. kannst du dich bei Beschwerden auch direkt an die Datenschutz-Aufsichtsbehörde wenden)

 **Löschung von Daten und Speicherdauer**

Sofern nicht anders angegeben, löschen wir deine Daten, sobald diese nicht mehr benötigt werden (z.B. deine E-Mail-Adresse nach der Abmeldung von unserem Newsletter). Eine Löschung oder Anonymisierung deiner Daten erfolgt auch dann, wenn eine durch ein Gesetz vorgeschriebene Speicherfrist abläuft (z.B. gesetzliche Speicherfristen für Zahlungstransaktionen). Bestimmte Daten müssen womöglich aus gesetzlichen Gründen länger aufbewahrt werden. Du kannst Auskunft über die gespeicherten personenbezogenen Daten verlangen. 

 **Datenerfassung in unseren Spielen**

Wenn du unsere Services nutzt, erfassen und speichern wir bestimmte Daten über dich, um unsere Spiele und Services bereitzustellen, dein Spielerlebnis insgesamt zu verbessern und dir maßgeschneiderte Angebote zu unterbreiten (z.B. bestimmte Angebote im Spiel, die dir nach deinem bisherigen Spiel gefallen könnten):

Temporäre eindeutige Gerätekennungen (z.B. IDFA und Android ID) und zufällige Gerätekennungen (client IDs) sowie nutzerbezogene Gerätekennzahlen (user IDs)

Fortschritt im Spiel und Spielverhalten (z.B. wie schnell du ein bestimmtes Level erreicht hast oder wie du deine Insel dekorierst)

In-App-Käufe (z.B. wieviele Diamanten du zu welchem Preis erworben hast)

Spielversion (z.B. v1.23.111)

Spracheinstellungen (z.B. Systemsprache Englisch)

IP Adresse (z.B. 96.92.316.Beispiel oder 2a02:7122:8337:1112:bdb2:651f:Beispiel)

Ungefähre Ortsbestimmung anhand IP-Bereich (z.B. „Berlin & Umgebung“)

Internetanbieter (z.B. „Unity Media“ or „Deutsche Telekom“)

Internet Geschwindigkeit (z.B. 120 Mbit)

Datum und Uhrzeit der Spiel-Session (z.B. 11:45 am 25.05.2018)

Browser und Version (z.B. Chrome v65 oder Safari 11.1)

Betriebssystem (z.B. MacOS, Android)

Hardware (z.B. Intel Prozessor)

Du weißt vielleicht schon, dass deine IP-Adresse und andere eindeutige Kennungen theoretisch auf dich oder das Gerät, auf dem du spielst, zurückgeführt werden können. _Zum Schutz deiner Privatsphäre_ löschen oder anonymisieren wir viele Kennungen in unserer Datenbank und die meisten technischen Daten nach deiner Spielsitzung. Alle anderen Daten werden ausschließlich zu statistischen Zwecken zur Optimierung des Spiels, für die Schaltung von interessenbezogener Werbung (weitere Informationen finden Sie weiter unten unter "Personalisierte Werbung") und um dir als Spieler ein personalisierteres Spielerlebnis zu bieten (z.B. automatische Einstellung der Schwierigkeit in Abhängigkeit von deinem Spielverhalten). _Der Zweck_ der vorübergehenden Speicherung dieser Daten ist es, eine Verbindung zu unseren Spielservern herzustellen, die für die Bereitstellung unserer Spiele und Services notwendig ist, sowie Ihnen ein persönlicheres Spielerlebnis zu bieten. _Rechtsgrundlage_ ist der Vertrag mit dir gemäß Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. b DSGVO sowie das berechtigte Interesse gemäß den europäischen Datenschutzanforderungen nach Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. f DSGVO. Darüber hinaus wenden wir die oben genannten Sicherheitsvorkehrungen an, um deine Daten zu schützen. 

**Mobile Apps und App Berechtigungen**

Wenn du unsere Spiele als mobile Apps herunterladen oder In-App-Artikel über eine App-Plattform (z.B. Apple App Store oder Google Play Store) kaufst, übermittelst du bestimmte Informationen an diese Plattform, insbesondere deine Kontodaten, z.B. Name, Gerätekennung, E-Mail-Adresse und Zahlungsinformationen. Wir haben keinen Einfluss auf diese Datenerhebung und sind nicht dafür verantwortlich.

Einige Funktionen unserer Spiele erfordern den Zugriff auf bestimmte Funktionen und Dienste auf deinem Gerät. Je nachdem, welches mobile Betriebssystem du verwendest, kann es erforderlich sein, dass du bestimmte App-Berechtigungen zulässt. Wir werden dir nun erklären, was diese Berechtigungen sind:

 **iOS**

Push-Benachrichtigungen: Wenn du im Popup-Fenster "Push-Benachrichtigungen zulassen" OK auswählst, erlaubst du der App, dich über bestimmte Ereignisse im Spiel zu informieren, auch wenn die App gerade nicht geöffnet ist. Du erhältst dann Benachrichtigungen in Form von Tönen, Nachrichten und/oder Symbolen (ein Bild oder eine Nummer auf dem App-Icon). 

Game Center: Wir bieten auch eine Verbindung zum Game Center Service von Apple, der den Apple Datenschutzbestimmungen unterliegt, die unter https://www.apple.com/privacy. verfügbar sind. Wenn du den Service nutzt, z.B. um Benachrichtigungen über Erfolge zu erhalten, sind die von dir freigegebenen persönlichen Informationen für andere Benutzer sichtbar und können von ihnen gelesen, gesammelt oder verwendet werden. Du musst dir überlegen, welche persönlichen Daten du angeben möchtest. 

 **Android**

Externer Speicher (Ändern oder Löschen deines externen Speichers, Lesen des Inhalts deines externen Speichers): Diese Funktionen ermöglichen es der App, Inhalte auf deinem Gerät zwischenzuspeichern. Die App verwendet dazu nur einen eigenen Speicherplatz. Andere Daten auf dem externen Speicher werden nicht gelöscht, verändert oder gelesen.

Internetverbindung (Internetdaten abrufen, vollen Netzwerkzugriff, Netzwerk- und Wi-Fi-Verbindungen anzeigen): Mit diesen Funktionen kann die App Daten aus dem Internet abrufen und feststellen, ob eine Verbindung zum Internet über ein Wi-Fi-Netzwerk oder über eine mobile Datenverbindung besteht. Damit soll verhindert werden, dass größere Datenmengen das womöglich begrenzte Datenvolumen verbrauchen.

Deaktivieren des Ruhezustandes: Mit dieser Funktion kann die App den Ruhezustand des Telefons deaktivieren (z.B. um Videos anzuzeigen, ohne den Bildschirm auszuschalten).

 _Zum Schutz deiner Privatsphäre_ sind alle App-Berechtigungen optional, mit Ausnahme der technischen Berechtigungen, die für die Ausführung der App erforderlich sind. Du kannst die Berechtigungen jederzeit ablehnen (durch Klicken auf „nein“ oder „nicht akzeptieren“ in deinen Geräteeinstellungen). Du kannst die Berechtigungen auch nachträglich widerrufen, indem du die entsprechenden Einstellungen auf deinem Gerät änderst. _Der Zweck_ der Anfrage nach diesen Berechtigungen ist es, dich und das Spiel auf dem Laufenden zu halten über Spiele-Updates, spielbezogene Neuigkeiten und Benachrichtigungen. _Rechtsgrundlage_ ist deine Einwilligung gemäß den europäischen Datenschutzbestimmungen nach Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. a DSGVO.

 **Verbinden mit Facebook**

Einige unserer Spiele kannst du direkt auf Facebook spielen oder das Spiel mit deinen Facebook-Accountdaten verbinden. In diesem Fall kannst du dich mit deinem Facebook-Account auf mehreren Geräten anmelden und deinen gespeicherten Spielstand auf verschiedenen Geräten synchronisieren. Wir werden deine Freundeslisten und Kontakte nicht speichern und es gibt keine permanente Verbindung zwischen dem Spiel und deinem Facebook-Account, du kannst dein Facebook-Profil jederzeit von dem Spiel trennen, das du gerade spielst. Der zugrundeliegende Service wird von Facebook bereitgestellt und weitere Details findest du in der Datenschutzerklärung von Facebook ([http://www.facebook.com/policy.php](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php)). Die Verbindung mit Facebook erlaubt uns nicht, ohne deine Erlaubnis etwas auf deiner Facebook-Seite zu veröffentlichen. Wir erhalten einige der folgenden Facebook-Kontoinformationen, je nachdem, welche Weitergabe du zulässt:

Öffentliche Profilinformationen (z.B. Facebook-Name, dein Profilbild und andere öffentliche Informationen usw.)

Freundesliste (Freunde, mit denen du auf Facebook verbunden bist)

E-Mail-Adresse (die E-Mail-Adresse, mit der du dich bei Facebook anmeldest)

Von Facebook spezifisch für das Spiel zugeteilte ID für dein Profil (nicht deine Facebook-ID)

Wir verwenden diese Informationen, um dein Spielerlebnis zu verbessern (z.B. kannst du sehen, welche deiner Freunde das gleiche Spiel wie du spielt und umgekehrt) und auch für Marktforschung und Werbung, aber nur nach Anonymisierung. 

 _Zum Schutz deiner Privatsphäre_ und der Privatsphäre deiner Freunde kannst du bei Facebook wählen, welche deiner Facebook-Informationen Sie mit uns teilen möchten (mit Ausnahme der erforderlichen Profilinformationen), und wir stellen sicher, dass personenbezogene Daten gelöscht oder anonymisiert werden, so dass sie in unseren Systemen nicht auf dich zurückgeführt werden können. Da sich einige der Facebook-Services in den USA und damit in einem Land außerhalb der EU und des EWR (in einem Drittland) befinden, sind weitere Schutzmaßnahmen erforderlich, um sicherzustellen, dass deine Daten in Übereinstimmung mit einem europäischen Datenschutzniveau geschützt sind. Facebook ist nach dem EU-US Privacy Shield für die werbebezogenen Services zertifiziert und hat damit ein ausreichendes Datenschutzniveau nachgewiesen ([https://www.facebook.com/about/privacyshield](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacyshield)). _Der Zweck_ der Erfassung und Speicherung dieser Informationen ist es, dich mit deinen Freunden auf Facebook zu verbinden, dir ein plattformübergreifendes Spielerlebnis zu bieten, deinen gespeicherten Spielstatus zu synchronisieren und personalisierte Werbung anzubieten. _Rechtsgrundlage_ ist deine Einwilligung – wenn du dich entscheidest deinen Facebook-Account zu verbinden - in Übereinstimmung mit den europäischen Datenschutzbestimmungen gemäß Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. a DSGVO.

 **Support und Kontaktformular**

Wir arbeiten mit Helpshift Inc. („Helpshift“) mit Sitz in den Vereinigten Staaten, die einen externen Online-Helpdesk und ein In-App-Supportsystem anbieten. Wenn du uns über unsere Spiele-Apps, über den Spiele-Support auf unserer Website oder Facebook kontaktierst, werden die folgenden Informationen von Helpshift streng nach unseren Anweisungen behandelt:

Spiel, das du spielst

Dein Name oder Spitzname

Deine E-Mail-Adresse 

Plattform, auf der du spielst

Art des Problems

Deine Sprache

Deine Benutzer-ID oder spielspezifische Facebook-ID

Deine Problembeschreibung

Deine hochgeladene Datei (optional)

Helpshift erfasst auch automatisch zusätzliche Informationen, wie z.B. deine IP-Adresse und die von deinem Gerät gesendeten Daten zur Bereitstellung und Verbesserung des Services (weitere Informationen findest du in dieser Datenschutzerklärung unter „Datenerfassung in unseren Spielen“ oder in der Helpshift Datenschutzerklärung: [https://www.helpshift.com/legal/privacy](https://www.helpshift.com/legal/privacy)). Die Informationen werden dann an einen Helpshift-Server in den USA übertragen. _Zum Schutz deiner Privatsphäre_ haben wir mit Helpshift einen Vertrag über die Datenverarbeitung abgeschlossen, in dem wir sicherstellen, dass deine Daten nur nach unseren Anweisungen und nicht für ihre eigenen Zwecke verwendet werden. Darüber hinaus erfolgt deine Anfrage über eine verschlüsselte Verbindung und wir verwenden das Prinzip der Datenminimierung, um nur solche Daten zu sammeln, die tatsächlich erforderlich sind, um deine Anfrage bestmöglich zu beantworten. Der Inhalt deiner Anfrage wird so lange gespeichert, wie du ein aktiver Spieler unserer Spiele bist, damit wir eine schnellere Antwort erhalten, falls du in Zukunft ein ähnliches Problem hast. Die Nutzung des Angebots von Helpshift dient der Beantwortung der zahlreichen Anfragen, die uns täglich erreichen. Helpshift hilft uns, unseren Kundenservice zu verbessern, damit wir schneller auf deine Nutzeranfragen reagieren können. _Rechtsgrundlage_ ist der Vertrag mit dir gemäß Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. b DSGVO und das berechtigte Interesse gemäß den europäischen Datenschutzanforderungen nach Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. f DSGVO, die wir gemeinsam mit unserem Datenschutzbeauftragten ausgewertet haben. Zum Schutz deiner Daten treffen wir zudem die oben genannten Sicherheitsvorkehrungen. 

 **(Personalisierte) Werbung**

Wir verwenden Werbetechnologien in unseren Spielen und tauschen Werbe-IDs mit externen Werbenetzwerken aus, um die personalisierte Werbung innerhalb unserer Spiele zu zeigen. Wir und unsere vertrauenswürdigen Partner erfassen und verarbeiten die Apple Werbe-ID (IDFA) auf iOS-Geräten und die Google Werbe-ID auf Android-Geräten, um interessenbezogene Werbung zu ermöglichen und den Erfolg der oben genannten Werbung zu messen. Werbe-IDs sind eindeutige, aber gleichzeitig nicht-personalisierte und nicht-permanente Identifikationsnummern, die von deinem Betriebssystem und Gerät bereitgestellt werden. Wie du die Werbetechnologien innerhalb der mobilen Apps aktivieren bzw. deaktivieren kannst, wird im Folgenden erläutert:

 **iOS**

Öffne die Anwendung „Einstellungen“ von iOS und wählen Sie den Menüpunkt „Datenschutz“ und dann den Unterpunkt „Werbung“. Wenn du die Option „Kein Ad-Tracking“ aktivierst, können wir nur begrenzte Maßnahmen ergreifen, wie z.B. die Identifizierung eindeutiger Nutzer oder die Betrugsbekämpfung. Im gleichen Menü kannst du jederzeit die IDFA löschen („Ad-ID zurücksetzen“), dann wird eine neue ID erstellt, die nicht mit den zuvor erfassten Daten zusammengeführt wird. 

**Android**

Öffne die Anwendung „Einstellungen“ und wählen Sie den Menüpunkt „Google“. Abhängig von deinem Gerät ist diese Option möglicherweise nicht im Hauptmenü sichtbar, aber du kannst die Suchfunktion oben im Menü „Einstellungen“ verwenden, um sie zu finden. Wähle dort den Unterpunkt „Anzeigen“ und aktiviere die Option „Opt out of Ads Personalisation“, um die Erstellung von Profilen und die Anzeige von interessenbezogener Werbung zu verhindern. Du kannst die Werbe-ID im gleichen Menü jederzeit löschen („Werbe-ID zurücksetzen“), dann wird eine neue ID erstellt, sodass die zuvor gesammelten Daten nicht zusammengeführt werden.

 _Zum Schutz deiner Privatsphäre_ speichern wir personenbezogene Daten nur vorübergehend. Zusätzlich kann der Nutzer die interessenbezogene Werbung in den Geräteeinstellungen wie oben beschrieben deaktivieren. Darüber hinaus stellen wir durch den Abschluss von Datenschutzvereinbarungen sicher, dass sich unsere externen Dienstleister auf ein hohes Datenschutzniveau verpflichten. _Der Zweck_ liegt darin, unsere Spiele zu verbessern und dem Spieler mehr personalisierte Werbung zu bieten. Die gesammelten Informationen helfen uns, unsere Webseiten und Spiele zu verbessern und gleichzeitig unsere Spiele für eine breite Spielerbasis kostenfrei zu halten. _Rechtsgrundlage_ ist das berechtigte Interesse gemäß den europäischen Datenschutzbestimmungen nach Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. f DSGVO, die wir gemeinsam mit unserem Datenschutzbeauftragten ausgewertet haben. Darüber hinaus wurde ein Vertrag über die Datenverarbeitung mit den externen Werbenetzwerken gemäß den Anforderungen des Art. 28 DSGVO geschlossen.

Zuletzt aktualisiert: März 2019
